calumetphoto.com 2013-05-08

# Digital cameras, lenses and photo gear at calumetphoto.com

**BY USING THE CALUMETPHOTO.COM WEB SITE, YOU CONSENT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TO CALUMETPHOTO.COM’S PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR THE PURPOSES STATED BELOW. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE OUR WEB SITE OR OUR SERVICES.**

Calumet Photographic, Inc., (“CalumetPhoto.com”, "us", "we" or "our") is committed to protecting your privacy. This policy covers how Calumet Photographic handles personal information that it collects and receives through our web site located at www.CalumetPhoto.com (the “Web Site”) at our Call Center and at Retail Stores. Personal information is any information about you that is personally identifiable such as your name, address, email address, phone number, and information about you that is not otherwise publicly available.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into CalumetPhoto.com’s Terms of Service. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully because by using CalumetPhoto.com or visiting a Calumet Photographic retail store, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of the Terms of Service, including this Privacy Policy and Calumet Photographic’s privacy practices. If you have any questions, please contact us by email at [privacy@CalumetPhoto.com](mailto:privacy@CalumetPhoto.com)

### What We Collect

Calumet Photographic collects personal information when you register with CalumetPhoto.com, when you purchase or order a product, subscribe to a service, register to receive catalogs, when you visit our Web Site, purchase something at one of our stores, when you enter promotions and sweepstakes sponsored by or affiliated with Calumet Photographic and when you participate in market research studies offered by or in conjunction with Calumet Photographic. Calumet Photographic may combine information that we have about you with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. We may also maintain a record of your product purchases.

When you visit the Web Site, we collect and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP Address, CalumetPhoto.com cookie information, and/or the web page(s) you visit.

When you register with CalumetPhoto.com, we may ask for personal information about you such as your name, mailing address, email address, birth date, gender, or other information. The information we request for registration purposes may change from time to time.

Children: Calumet Photographic does not permit children under the age of 13 to register with us. If we later learn that a user is under the age of 13, we will terminate the account and delete the user's information. Inherent in the Calumet Photographic service is the responsibility of parents and/or guardians to ensure that their children's privacy is protected.

### What We Share

We use the personal information you provide for internal purposes, such as confirming and tracking your order, subscription or registration, analyzing trends and statistics, informing you of our new products, services and offers, and providing you with information from and about Calumet Photographic, Inc. From time to time we might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities that we believe to be trustworthy partners. In such cases we might share and cross-reference information, including personal information about you that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us in-store, online or through our Call Center. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about our products that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes. We may also use your personal information to customize the advertising and content you see on the Web Site and improve our products and services.

We may contract with service providers, including companies or persons that provide certain services including credit card processing, shipping, data management, promotional services, etc. We provide our service providers with the information needed for them to perform these services.

Calumet Photographic may announce voluntary promotional programs such as sweepstakes and contests. Participation in these promotions may require you to share personal information with us. This information may be shared with external third parties for the purpose of the administration, operation, or fulfillment of the promotion. Subscribers who do not wish this information to be disclosed to third parties may decline participation in these optional promotions.

If you visit the Web Site by clicking through a link or promotion located on another web site, or if you registered for our site through an online service that provides a universal registration service, we will store the ID of that affiliate site in our database along with your account information. This allows us to credit the affiliate site for any subsequent purchases made by you on our Web Site. We may also use this information to identify additional products and services that may be of interest to you.

CalumetPhoto.com may analyze IP addresses of visitors to the Web Site in the aggregate for purposes including system administration and the gathering of broad demographic information. We do not link IP addresses to you personally, except when you make a purchase through the Web Site, in which case we will record your computer's IP address to enable us to identify fraudulent credit card use. We reserve the right to share this information with the credit card issuer or with law enforcement authorities if we determine, or are notified, that use of the credit card was fraudulent.

Although unlikely, in certain instances we may disclose your personal information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, to Calumet Photographic, Inc. or to others. We may also disclose your personal information when we believe the law requires it.

We reserve the right to transfer personal information we have collected about you if Calumet Photographic, Inc. is acquired by or merged with another company, in the case of a sale of all or substantially all of Calumet Photographic’s assets, or in the unlikely event of a bankruptcy.

If you do not wish to have your personal information shared with third parties who are not involved with the fulfillment of Calumet Photographic products or services that you have requested, please let us know by sending us an email at [privacy@CalumetPhoto.com](mailto:privacy@CalumetPhoto.com).

### Use of Cookies and Other Technologies

We use cookies and other technologies such as pixel tags and clear gifs to personalize the Web Site to your interests and to facilitate an automatic log-in process. A cookie is a text file placed on your hard disk by a web page server that is uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. CalumetPhoto.com allows advertisers on our Web Site to set and access cookies on your computer. Use of cookies by advertisers on our Web Site is subject to the privacy policies of those advertisers and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you are not comfortable with the use of cookies on your computer, you may set your computer preferences to accept or decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience all features of the Web Site.

The Web Site and HTML e-mails sent by CalumetPhoto.com may contain single-pixel gifs called web beacons that allow us to count users who have visited a specific web page or opened an e-mail, conduct research on partner web sites for auditing purposes, to access your CalumetPhoto.com cookie to identify when you visit third party web sites, or to report aggregate demographic or usage information to our partners. The Web Site may also contain third party web beacons for the purpose of determining the effectiveness of joint promotional or advertising campaigns.

### Setting your Preferences

Calumet Photographic respects your right to control how your personal information is used. You can edit your CalumetPhoto.com Account Information and modify your preferences, including your email preferences, at any time, by logging into your account on the CalumetPhoto.com Web Site. Users may also opt out of having personal information shared with unaffiliated third parties not involved with the fulfillment of products or services you requested by following the instructions contained in the messages they receive from us or our affiliates or by sending us an email at privacy@CalumetPhoto.com. We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the CalumetPhoto.com service, such as service announcements and administrative messages that are considered part of your CalumetPhoto.com account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

### Legal Disclaimer

We disclaim, and you agree, that Calumet Photographic, Inc. will not be liable to you for any damages caused by acts or events beyond our reasonable control including, without limitation, acts of God, fires, floods, acts of terrorism, wars, civil disturbances, sabotage, accidents, labor disputes, governmental actions, and failures or delays of transportation that result in our disclosure of your personal information.

### Security

Calumet Photographic takes reasonable security measures to protect user information under our company's control against loss, misuse, or alteration. Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, access to your personal information is limited to only those employees and third parties with a specific need to retrieve this information.

The Web Site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Calumet Photographic is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. CalumetPhoto.com encourages users to be aware when they leave our Web Site and to read the privacy statements of other web sites you visit. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by our Web Site. Calumet Photographic is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third party sites.

### International Transfer of Information

Calumet Photographic may transfer your personal information from your country or jurisdiction of residence to other countries or jurisdictions. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions, please note that the United States does not have the same data protection laws as the EU. By providing your personal information to Calumet Photographic, you consent to: (i) the use of your personally identifiable information for the uses described in this Privacy Policy; and (ii) the transfer of your personal information to the United States.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Calumet Photographic reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, update, change, modify or revise this Privacy Statement, the CalumetPhoto.com Web Site or our services by posting such change, update or modification on the Site. Any such addition, update, change, modification or revision will be effective immediately upon posting. If we materially change how we use your personal information, we will notify you via e-mail.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or our information-handling practices, please contact us by e-mail at [privacy@CalumetPhoto.com](mailto:privacy@CalumetPhoto.com) or write to us:

Calumet Photographic, Inc.  
Attn: CalumetPhoto.com Privacy Policy  
900 W. Bliss Street  
Chicago, Illinois 60642

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits the customers of Calumet Photographic who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [privacy@CalumetPhoto.com](mailto:privacy@CalumetPhoto.com) or write us:

Calumet Photographic, Inc.  
Attn: California Privacy Rights  
900 W. Bliss Street  
Chicago, Illinois 60642

Policy last updated: October 30, 2011
